-One of them shows up at last. -What are you?
-終於有個妖怪鬼鬼祟祟地現身了 -你是誰？
Enemies passed water in fear when hearing my name on the battlefield.
敵人在戰場上聽到我的名字都會嚇尿
Don't be surprised.
你們可別被嚇到
Shinigami Mercenaries. My name is Ushiuchibo.
死神僱傭兵團，牛打坊
USHIUCHIBO: DEMON FROM JAPANESE FABLES
（牛打坊：日本怪談中）
WHO HUNTS ANIMALS WITH DEADLY POISON
（使用致命毒藥獵殺動物的妖怪）
What's that?
那是什麼東西？
Just some pricks hunting Joseon demons.
就是獵殺朝鮮妖怪的混帳啦
-Doesn't seem like much in person. -Whatever you are, go sit over there.
-本人看起來也不怎麼樣嘛 -不管你是什麼東西，老實坐在那邊
The Joseon mountain gods are mingling now.
朝鮮山神正在講話
Why is his head shaped like that?
他的腦袋為什麼是那種形狀啊？
You shits dare look down on me?
你們幾個小角色居然敢小看我？
You all breathed in a fog full of deadly poison.
你們都吸入了致命毒霧
You have a death wish?
你想死嗎？
You're the ones who will be dying!
要死的人是你們啊！
Only I can neutralize my poison.
只有我能解開我的毒藥
I heard there was a poison bender, so I guess that's you, huh?
聽說僱傭兵團裡有個下毒的妖怪 應該就是你吧？
-You poisoned the Gyeongseong wells too. -I see you've heard of my reputation.
-京城水井裡的毒也是你下的 -看來你有聽過我的名聲
Hand over the treasures. Then, I'll spare their lives.
交出寶物，我就放過他們
Don't be ridiculous.
別開玩笑了
Wh--
這…
You have an hour at most.
你們最多能支撐一小時
Your body will be bled white, and you will die in pain.
你們的身體會失血，變得慘白 最後在痛苦中死去
-Not to a wuss like him! -Well?
-不能死在他這種廢物手上！ -怎樣？
-Will you give it up to save them? Or-- -Take it.
-你要為了救他們而讓步嗎？還是… -拿去
No, Yeon! You can't give him the treasures!
不要啊，阿硯！你不能把寶物給他！
What choice is there?
還有選擇嗎？
To catch the hare, you enter its burrow.
想要抓住兔子，必須進入兔子洞
-A hare? -Here you go.
-兔子？ -給你
Just like that?
這麼容易？
The antidote.
解藥交出來
Give it.
給我
Now that I think about it, the easiest way to get an antidote…
仔細一想 最容易拿到解藥的辦法…
Is to use violence.
就是使用暴力
For ages, we've called this, "hare and hounds."
我們一直把這叫做“獵犬追兔”遊戲
Oh, gosh. Sumimasen.
天哪，不好意思
We all have trust issues, you know.
我們信不過任何人
-Shall we begin? -Yes.
-我們開始吧？ -嗯
-Geez. You packed all that? -Shall I slice him, shred him or peel him?
-天哪，妳帶來這麼多工具？ -是切片、切絲還是剝皮呢？
-Let's just chop him up. -No. Then he'll die too soon.
-直接把他剁了吧 -不行，那樣死得太快了
I don't like his face, so let's touch up his chin and nose.
我不喜歡他的臉 我們給他整整下巴和鼻子吧
That should fix him up.
那樣就好看了
You crazy bastards!
你們這些瘋子！
-Go with that one. -Sure!
-就用那個吧 -好吧！
Now I'll break your bones one at a time, until we get the antidote.
我會一次敲碎一塊骨頭 直到我們拿到解藥
Where did Ushiuchibo go?
牛打坊去哪裡了？
EPISODE 10
（第 10 集）
I hear a sound.
我聽到一個聲音
It's Ushiuchibo.
是牛打坊
There's someone next to him.
他身邊有人
That punk wants to take the treasures for himself!
那個臭小子想獨吞寶物！
That selfish prick.
那個自私鬼
I'll go take a look.
我去看看
Yuki, wait for me!
宥淇，等等我！
Shall we take turns?
我們要不要輪流來？
I haven't even started yet.
我還沒開始呢
Hey.
喂
-I'm the strongest mountain god. -True, true.
-我是最強大的山神 -沒錯
It's harder not to hit you at full force.
要克制自己別使出全力打你 實在很難啊
For a mountain god who lost her country…
一個祖國淪陷的山神…
That sure is a lot of talk.
還在這裡大放厥詞
Starting now, I'll hit you thrice.
從現在起，我要打你三拳
Provide the antidote by then or I crack your head.
在那之前交出解藥 否則我打爛你的腦袋
Squirm all you want.
盡情掙扎吧
Because you will all die here today.
反正你們今天都會死在這裡
Is that a laugh?
你在笑嗎？
Hong-joo.
紅酒
Move away!
讓開！
I couldn't move my body.
我的身體不能動了
This is his specialty.
這是他的特長
Get out of my way.
你讓開
-Strike one. -Wait!
-一拳 -等一下！
Strike two.
兩拳
Boss!
團長！
Strike three.
三拳
He's dead. You shouldn't have killed him.
他死了，妳不該殺死他的
He kept pissing me off.
誰叫他一直激怒我
Now there's three of them left.
現在還剩三個妖怪
You knew from the start, didn't you? That he spits poison when cornered.
你一開始就知道對不對？ 你知道他會在危急時刻口吐毒藥
Yeah.
嗯
Why didn't you tell us?
你為什麼不告訴我們？
You two weren't interested in anything but my treasure in the first place.
你們兩個一開始只關心我的寶物
Gosh, you evil bastard.
天哪，你這個惡毒的混蛋
We must get out of here now.
我們必須馬上離開這裡
-The mercenaries will come at his call. -We'll kill them all.
-僱傭兵團會被他的喊聲引來的 -我們殺光他們
Not in our state.
以我們目前的狀態不可能
Let's get out, and find a way to neutralize the poison. Come on.
我們先出去想辦法解毒吧，快走
Wait for me!
等等我！
I'm the only one unscathed anyway.
畢竟只有我毫髮無傷
Please save me. Save me! It's here!
救救我！救命啊！那東西來了！
Lord Lee Rang!
李朗大人！
Over here, you bastards! Boss!
來啊，你們這些混蛋！老大！
Be careful! They can withstand blade slashes!
小心！他們是砍不死的！
Hey, get Mrs. Boss to the room first!
先帶頭目夫人回房間吧！
Hurry and go upstairs! Leave this to me!
快點上樓！這裡交給我！
Come here! Die! Die!
過來！去死！
-Hurry! We have to go too! -Die, you all!
-快點！我們也必須離開！ -你們都去死吧！
Geez! Why you--
天哪，你怎麼…
Quick!
快！
I'm scared. Gosh, I'm scared!
我好怕，天哪，我好怕！
Whatever happens here tonight, stay out of it.
無論今晚發生什麼，你都不要插手
Don't come, you shit!
別過來，混蛋！
-Jae-yoo! -Our roommate's the best!
-載宇！ -我們的室友最棒了！
Please help me!
救救我！
-What do we do? -What do you mean "what"?
-怎麼辦？ -什麼叫怎麼辦？
Please open the door!
快開門啊！
He'll die out there!
他會死在外面的！
Hey! Have you lost your mind?
妳瘋了嗎？
Is anyone there?
裡面有人嗎？
-Don't ever come out of my room. -And you?
-千萬別離開我的房間 -那你呢？
I'll get the others.
我去救其他人
Let me come with you.
我陪你去
I'll be back soon.
我很快就回來
No!
不！
Yeo-hee!
汝熙！
This is unbelievable!
難以置信！
Ushiuchibo is dead?
牛打坊死了？
Joseon's mountain gods are this strong?
朝鮮山神有這麼強大嗎？
Gosh. The more I know, the more fascinating he is.
天哪 我了解得愈多，就愈是對他著迷
Don't be ridiculous! Ushiuchibo is the weakest of us all!
別傻了！ 牛打坊是我們之中最弱的一個！
I wonder where that lovely nine-tailed fox went.
不知道那隻可愛的九尾狐去哪了
Was it west?
是西邊嗎？
Yuki, you can't act alone!
宥淇，妳不能單獨行動！
-I'll just go look around! -Yuki!
-我只是四處看看！ -宥淇！
Damn. Where the hell are they?
該死，他們到底在哪裡？
Hong-joo, hang in there. Okay?
紅酒，撐著點，好嗎？
Is it just me, or did we pass here earlier?
是我的錯覺嗎？ 我們是不是來過這裡？
What the hell is this forest?
這片樹林怎麼回事？
It's from the picture in Room 404.
這是404號房的那幅畫
One of them can use an illusion charm.
有個妖怪會使用幻術
They have someone with such notable skills?
他們有人會用那麼厲害的法術？
I guess he must be the boss.
我猜他一定是團長
-What's wrong with him? -It's the poison.
-他怎麼了？ -毒藥的緣故
My sight has been getting blurry for some time too.
我的視力從剛才就開始模糊了
Hey, you okay?
喂，你沒事吧？
Get your hands off me.
別用你的手碰我
Oh, you prefer my feet then? Hey, you okay?
那你要我用腳嗎？喂，你沒事吧？
Hey, Moo-yeong! Hey!
無影！醒醒！
Yeon.
阿硯
This poison is much more lethal than I thought.
這毒藥比我想像的要命多了
No, no. You can't collapse here, okay?
不行，妳不能倒在這裡，知道嗎？
Hold on.
等一下
I don't like this at all.
我一點都不喜歡這樣
You're a mercenary, huh?
妳是僱傭兵吧？
-Is she your lover? -She's my friend. Why?
-她是你的愛人嗎？ -她是我的朋友，怎麼了？
She's not your girlfriend then? What a relief.
那就不是女朋友囉？總算鬆了一口氣
I'm Yuki.
我是宥淇
One moment.
等一下
What's that?
搞什麼？
-Do you like snowmen? -What?
-你喜歡雪人嗎？ -什麼？
Because Yuki gifts snowmen to her lovers.
宥淇會送雪人給她喜歡的人
Oh, whoa!
哇！
This represents my love.
這代表我的愛
-Hey, hey! -Sheesh!
-喂！ -真是的！
Why you little brat. This one's mine!
死丫頭，這個人是我的！
You crazy bitch! Yuki will have him!
瘋婆子！宥淇要搶走他！
-Wanna fight? -Winner gets to have him.
-想打架嗎？ -誰贏了，他就歸誰
Hey, don't discuss my ownership with each other.
別自顧自地討論我的歸屬啊
-Stay out of it!
-你別管！
-Stop it. Enough. -So unfair.
-別打了，夠了 -不公平
You're the one being unfair. This one drank a bunch of poison.
妳這樣才不公平，她剛中過毒
Yuki!
宥淇！
-Yuki! -It's Oogama.
-宥淇！ -是大蝦蟆
-I have to go. -Why is that?
-我得走了 -為什麼？
This would be your chance to take the treasures, no?
這不是妳奪取寶物的好時機嗎？
You're right. But boss hates when I move on my own.
你說得沒錯 但是團長不喜歡我單獨行動
I see.
這樣啊
So where is that boss of yours?
那你們團長在哪裡？
You'll see him soon.
你很快就會見到他的
Yeon! You have to catch her!
阿硯！你必須抓住她！
Ice.
冰
Oh, shit!
該死！
Damn it.
哎呦
Geez, you almost got me!
天哪，差點被妳的法術傷到
-You know about me? -Yeah.
-你知道我？ -嗯
I heard the rumor, all right. The ice cream-like demon mercenary.
我是聽過傳言沒錯 像冰淇淋一樣的妖怪僱傭兵
My real name is Yuki-onna.
我的真名是雪女
YUKI-ONNA: SNOW LADY, SNOW SPIRIT FROM JAPANESE FABLES
（雪女：日本怪談中的雪妖）
Yuki-onna, want to strike a deal with me?
雪女，要不要和我做個交易？
A deal?
交易？
You…
妳…
-You came looking for these treasures, no? -That's…
-妳是來找這些寶物的吧？ -那是…
-Will you give them to Yuki? -Be patient.
-你願意把它們交給宥淇？ -耐心一點
I'll give you one treasure. If you'll exchange it for the antidote.
我可以給妳一件寶物 只要妳拿解藥來換
-Stop! If something happens to you-- -I don't care.
-不要！如果你出事的話… -我不在乎
That's enough.
夠了
I'm dying, right?
我要死了對不對？
You won't die.
妳不會死的
What if I turn into one those monsters and I don't even recognize you, Rang?
阿朗，如果我變成那種怪物 連你都認不出來怎麼辦？
I won't let you.
有我在就不會
I have a question.
我有一個問題
Why did you save me back then?
當初你為什麼要救我？
You know, the first time you came to the club.
你第一次來俱樂部的時候
That day…
那天
I was feeling so miserable.
我覺得自己很可憐
I thought about just dying.
我想過一死了之
But then I saw you on stage.
然後我看到了舞台上的妳
You were singing a song no one was hearing…
妳唱著一首沒有人聆聽的歌
with such a happy face.
笑得那麼開心
I don't know why, but when I heard you singing…
不知道為什麼，聽到妳的歌聲…
I thought I should live.
我就想要活下去
Thank you.
謝謝你
For staying here by my side this very moment.
謝謝你在這一刻陪在我身邊
If I were alone…
如果是我一個人…
I would've been so scared.
我一定會很害怕
I'll stay by your side, for the rest of my life.
我的餘生都會陪在妳身邊
Lee Yeon gave it.
這是李硯給我的
I've dreamt of this moment so many times.
這一刻，我已經夢想過無數遍了
But why today?
為什麼非要是今天？
I…
我…
I was perverse from birth.
我從出生起就執拗任性
I used to stumble at the pettiest misfortunes.
只要碰上一點點挫折就會栽跟頭
All my life…
我的一生…
I lived running from my past.
始終在逃避過去
But don't intend to stumble or run anymore.
但我不想再栽跟頭或者逃避了
Because I have you.
因為我有妳
Yeo-hee, what's wrong?
汝熙，怎麼了？
I'm cold.
我好冷
You're burning up!
妳發燒了！
What should I do, Yeon?
阿硯，我該怎麼辦？
Smile a little.
笑一笑嘛
Don't touch me.
別碰我
Until our wedding,
在我們舉行婚禮前
I'll save your dignity.
我會保全妳的尊嚴
-I'll get off here. -You aren't going home, ma'am?
-我在這裡下車 -小姐不回家嗎？
I'd like to walk.
我想走回去
Let her off.
讓她下車
Why is Yeo-hee running so late?
汝熙為什麼還不回來？
I hope nothing's happened to her.
希望她別出事啊
No way.
不會的
Lord Lee Yeon and Lee Rang are at the hotel too.
李硯大人和李朗大人也在飯店
Eun-ho!
恩好！
-Eun-ho. -Ma'am! What are you doing here?
-恩好 -店長！妳在這裡做什麼？
Who was that man just now?
剛剛那個男人是誰？
-Ryuhei Kato, the Chief Commissioner. -Your brother-in-law?
-加藤龍平，首席專員 -妳的姊夫嗎？
Yeah, but he's about to become my husband.
沒錯，但他就要成為我的丈夫了
Now what's that about?
怎麼回事？
They want me to marry that man.
他們要我嫁給他
Eun-ho.
恩好
You, listen to me carefully.
妳仔細聽我講
That man…
那個男人…
isn't human.
不是人類
What do you mean the Chief Commissioner isn't human?
妳說首席專員不是人類是什麼意思？
I saw him.
我看到他了
With my own eyes.
親眼看到的
-Lord Lee Yeon! -Don't come!
-李硯大人！ -別過來！
If he's not human, what is he?
如果他不是人類，那他是什麼？
I don't know his original form.
我不知道他的本體是什麼
But Eun-ho, don't ever get close to him.
但是恩好，千萬不要靠近他
Could this be the secret my sister saw?
這會不會就是我姊姊發現的祕密？
She knew. That's why that bastard killed her.
她早就知道，所以那個混蛋殺了她
Forget it, okay? You must forget.
忘記吧，妳必須忘記這件事
-He's not someone you can deal with. -Then what should I do?
-他這種人妳惹不起的 -那我該怎麼辦？
Get married to the enemy of my sister and my country,
嫁給姊姊和祖國的敵人
and live deceiving myself?
自欺欺人地生活嗎？
What the hell did we fight for?
我們究竟是為什麼而戰？
-This… -What about this dynamite?
-這個… -這箱炸藥是怎麼回事？
I will do it.
我去做
-Even if I must grab and die with him-- -Why would you, ma'am?
-就算要我拉著他同歸於盡… -店長，為什麼要這樣？
I…
我…
I've lived much longer than you can imagine.
我活的時間比妳想像的要長得多
I suffered all kinds of storms of life on this land.
我在這片土地上經歷過種種風雨
But what can I do?
可我有什麼辦法呢？
I still find Joseon to be beautiful.
在我眼裡，朝鮮依然很美
And you fighting to protect it…
妳拚命保護它的樣子…
is seemingly beautiful to me.
在我眼中也很美
You can't do it alone.
妳不能一個人去
I have an idea.
我有個辦法
I'll do it.
我願意
What?
什麼？
I said, I'll get married.
我說，我願意結婚
-Here. -The antidote?
-給 -解藥嗎？
-That girl gave it to you? -Yeah.
-那個女孩給你的嗎？ -嗯
-Why? -In exchange for the ruler.
-為什麼？ -為了交換金尺
-What? Gosh. -You yielded it to a Japanese demon?
-什麼？天哪 -你居然把它讓給了一個日本妖怪？
Well, yeah. I needed to save you guys first, no?
是啊，我得先救你們嘛
Do you think it's really an antidote?
你覺得這真的是解藥嗎？
I wouldn't know.
我怎麼知道？
What do you think it is?
你覺得是什麼？
I say it's an antidote.
應該是解藥
Don't eat it.
不要吃
-You wouldn't save us. I don't trust you. -Same here.
-你不會救我們的，我不信任你 -彼此彼此
At the very least, don't gamble with Hong-joo's life.
至少不要拿紅酒的性命賭博
If we're gambling.
既然要賭博
-Hey! -This would be one, right?
-喂！ -這樣才像樣吧？
-Yeon! -Goodness.
-阿硯！ -天哪
If I don't wake up, it's poison.
如果我醒不過來，那就是毒藥
Crazy fool.
瘋子
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
Yeon.
阿硯
Oh, shit.
該死
Let's go, let's go!
快走！
Hey, hey, I saved you. I did!
喂，我有救你喔，真的！
I saved you this time! I did!
這次是我救你的，真的！
Gosh, you idiot!
天哪，你這個笨蛋！
You ran over to us earlier, like, all--
你剛才衝過來救我們
It was super cool, right?
超酷的對不對？
I just happened upon you two, that's all.
我只是碰巧遇到你們而已
Don't get the wrong idea.
不要自作多情
Way to ruin a good compliment.
好好的讚美都被你毀了
We each serve a different boss.
我們各為其主
If they become enemies, we have no choice but to fight.
如果他們成為敵人 那我們也只能互鬥了
Say that when that actually happens.
到那時再說吧
Now, we're one big family of roomies.
現在，我們是一個室友大家庭
Me, Jae-yoo, and…
我、載宇，還有…
Hey, what's your name?
你叫什麼名字？
Well, just call me whatever. I'm fine with "hey" or "underboss."
叫我什麼都可以 “喂”或者“副頭目”都可以
-You don't have a name? -Just tell us.
-你沒有名字嗎？ -告訴我們吧
-I don't want to say. -You serious?
-我不想說 -搞什麼？
Why not? We survived death together, no?
為什麼不說呢？ 我們是共患難的兄弟嘛
-Lee M-- Yeon. -A what? "Yeon"?
-李…緣 -什麼？“緣”？
-Wh-- -Lee! Mi-yeon!
-是… -李！米緣！
Well, you have a pretty name for a bandit gang member.
土匪幫的人居然有這麼美的名字
Hey! Boss gave me that name.
喂，這名字是老大幫我取的
"Lee" after boss' surname. "Mi" for rice. "Yeon" for relationships.
“李”是老大的姓氏 “米”是米飯，“緣”是緣分
It means to eat rice heartily and live a long life. Geez!
寓意是盡情地吃米飯 長命百歲啦！
-All right, Mi-yeon. -Mi-yeon, paw!
-知道了，米緣 -米緣，握手！
Mi-yeon or Lee Yeon: potato potahto! And Hong-joo is even tackier, you--
米緣也好，李硯也好，都差不多！ “紅酒”這名字更俗氣，你…
-But Lord Lee Rang-- -Wait!
-可是李朗大人… -等等！
-You think boss and his missus is safe? -Oh, right!
-老大和他女朋友沒事吧？ -對喔！
Lord Lee Yeon will kill me if something happens to him!
如果他出事的話 李硯大人會殺了我！
Yeon…
阿硯…
Yeon!
阿硯！
Moo-yeong, what do we do?
無影，怎麼辦？
Yeon is--
阿硯他…
Hey! Why, that's nothing to joke about!
喂！這是可以開玩笑的事情嗎！
Sorry. This was an antidote after all.
對不起，這果然是解藥
-Moo-yeong, let's hurry and take it. -Oh, no.
-無影，我們快吃下去吧 -別急
Not for free.
不是免費的
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
What are they like?
他們是什麼樣子？
Aside from the fox, the others are weak from drinking poison.
除了那隻狐狸 其他人都因為中毒而身體虛弱
-Is that so? -But I gave him the antidote.
-是嗎？ -但是我有給他解藥
-Why, you crazy-- -Yuki always has a reason.
-妳這個瘋… -宥淇做事向來有她的道理
What reason, what?
什麼道理？
Ta-da!
看！
I exchanged the antidote for this.
我用解藥換來了這個
Wow!
哇！
It's the real deal!
是真的！
It's really it!
是真的沒錯！
-What are they plotting? -Guess they need an ally.
-他們有什麼詭計？ -我猜他們需要一位盟友
And the other two? How were they?
另外兩個呢？他們怎麼樣？
I fought the female mountain god.
我和那個女山神交手了
She was pretty tough, despite the poison.
她在中毒的情況下還是很強悍
Yet you still gave them the antidote?
那妳還把解藥給他們？
Well, they don't know what you can do, Nyudo.
他們不知道你的本領，入道
More excellent bodies the better.
強悍的身體愈多愈好
You've got a point.
有道理
Hold on to this, Yuki.
宥淇，妳把它保管好
Give me the antidote.
給我解藥
-On one condition. -A condition?
-有一個條件 -條件？
You two made it this far for my treasures, huh?
你們兩個走到這一步 是為了我的寶物吧？
But we have a mutual enemy now.
但是我們現在有共同的敵人了
The mercenaries.
僱傭兵團
I'll give you the antidote and you catch them with me.
我給你們解藥 你們和我一起抓住他們
-That's my condition. -Geez. I'm all in.
-這就是我的條件 -好啦，算我一個
Cheon Moo-yeong.
千無影
I don't need your help.
我不需要你幫忙
You think I'm doing this because you're so adorable?
你以為我是因為你可愛才幫你的嗎？
Even if we end each other, we must get out first, no?
即便我們要爭個你死我活 也得先出去吧？
And one of the treasures you're so obsessed with is in their hands.
而且有一件你痴迷的寶物 還在他們手裡
Swallow your ego and take it.
放下自尊接受吧
Mercenaries or not, if I were Yeon, I'd have left you to die.
拋開僱傭兵團不談 如果我是阿硯，我是不會救你的
You're red-white mask.
畢竟你是紅白面具人
Why would you try to save me too?
那你為什麼要救我？
I need your talents.
我需要你的天賦
The girl we saw earlier.
我們之前看到的女孩
She's a demon who controls snow and ice. You control fire.
是操控冰雪的妖怪，而你可以操控火
And what if the mountain gods chip in?
如果山神和他們聯手呢？
Four Japanese demons and two mountain gods, it's six to one.
四個日本妖怪和兩位山神對付你 等於六對一
That's the real goal of this operation.
這才是這次行動的真正目的
But what if Hong-joo and Moo-yeong sides with us?
但是如果紅酒和無影與我們聯手呢？
What if this becomes a battle between the mercenaries and the mountain gods?
如果這變成 僱傭兵團和山神之間的戰鬥呢？
How many wishes do I have left?
我還剩幾次許願的機會？
Wishes?
許願？
I still have some left, right?
還剩幾次吧？
This is my last wish.
這是我最後的願望
Get out of this room.
離開這個房間
And stay as far away as you can.
走得愈遠愈好
No.
不要
Then promise me one thing.
那就答應我一件事
If I change…
如果我變身…
Kill me with your own hands.
你要親手殺死我
No.
不行
I'll die with you.
我要陪妳一起死
Foxes only love one woman until the day they die.
狐狸到死只愛一個女人
You know, I really liked Gyeongseong.
其實我很喜歡京城的
The lights at the club.
俱樂部的燈光
The gorgeous stage costumes.
華麗的舞台服裝
The jewels at our boutique.
我們洋品店的首飾
It was filled with sparkles everywhere.
到處都亮晶晶的
But what shined the brightest in Gyeongseong was…
但是京城最閃耀的東西…
It was you, Lee Rang.
是你啊，李朗
Yeo-hee. Yeo-hee!
汝熙、汝熙！
She's still breathing but-- No, don't die!
還有呼吸，但是…不要死！
Yeo-hee, wake up. Wake up!
汝熙，快醒醒！
Lord Lee Rang.
李朗大人
-Boss. -Lord Lee Rang.
-老大 -李朗大人
Honey, I cooked some jeon for you!
老婆，我做了煎餅給妳吃！
My goodness! Don't drink on an empty stomach!
天哪！不要空著肚子喝酒啦！
I find your unconditional kindness quite frightening at times.
我覺得你無條件的關懷 有時候真的很可怕
I'm frightening?
我可怕？
I wonder how a kind person like you can endure living with me.
真不知道像你這樣善良的人 是如何忍受和我一起生活的
I'm proud of myself too.
我自己也很自豪
I still find you amazing.
我到現在還是覺得妳不可思議
If not you, who else could endure it?
除了妳，還有誰撐得住啊？
Being the owner of the Stream of the Dead. A job that is heavy as hell.
三途川主人的擔子多麼沉重啊
An owner in name only.
所謂的主人只是徒有虛名
I'm more like a powerless warden.
我更像是沒有權力的典獄長
Neither allowed to interfere in the human world,
既不能干涉人類的世界
nor completely neglect it.
又不能完全無視
I can't fight nor protect anyone.
不能對抗，也不能保護任何人
But you raised those kids instead.
但是妳把那幾個孩子養大了
Though Moo-yeong got a bit crooked in the very end.
雖然無影最後走上了歪路
They were all good mountain gods.
他們當初都是很好的山神啊
And you were a good teacher.
妳也是一位好老師
A good teacher, you say?
好老師？
That's why I believe they'll make the right choice in the end. They will win.
所以我相信他們最終 會做出正確的選擇，他們會贏的
Am I drunk?
我是不是喝醉了？
You look handsome for some reason.
你看上去莫名帥氣
Really? Have another drink.
真的嗎？再喝一杯吧
We're out of drinks. I'll go get some more.
沒有酒了，我再去拿一些
-Honey. -Yes?
-老公 -嗯？
Want to go to the theater tomorrow?
明天要不要去劇院？
-To the theater? You will? -Yeah.
-劇院？妳想去嗎？ -嗯
Yeon once told me this.
阿硯曾經告訴過我
To go out and see the world instead of just being pent-up in here.
多出去看看世界，不要天天窩在這裡
Well, I'd love to! I'll be right back.
我當然想去啦！我馬上回來
I wonder if the King of Five Paths will come to the theater.
不知道五道轉輪王會不會來劇院
I must find out what's unfolding around the stone and ruler.
我必須查清楚 守護石和金尺是怎麼回事
This guy knows how to cure her?
這個人有辦法治癒她？
Hurry and tell him, Mr. Jindo.
珍島先生，快告訴他吧
Tell me! Or else, you're coming with me to die!
告訴我！不然你就跟我一起死！
An innocent mermaid can't be sacrificed in a fight between our bosses, no?
雙方主人之間的戰鬥 沒必要犧牲無辜的人魚，對不對？
You don't want that either, huh?
你也不想那樣吧？
I just happened to hear something.
我只是剛好聽到了一段話
A Yacha?
夜叉？
What if we get unlucky and one of our guys get hurt?
萬一我們運氣不好 有自己人受傷怎麼辦？
Don't leave the room if possible. But if someone gets bitten…
盡量不要離開房間 如果有人被咬傷…
Give them some brewed iris pistil.
拿鳶尾花的雌蕊煮水給他們喝
A pistil of an iris. Will that work?
鳶尾花的雌蕊，有用嗎？
Moo-yeong created the demon, so it should work.
那妖怪是無影養出來的 他的辦法應該有用
How do we get that at this hour? Even if we go outside--
這麼晚了，我們去哪裡找雌蕊？ 就算我們出去…
We must save her before it's too late.
我們必須趁早救她
-You're sleeping? -It's in the hotel restaurant!
-你睡著啦？ -在飯店餐廳！
Bonjour, mademoiselle. Bonjour, monsieur.
各位先生女士，大家好
It's a French restaurant. I saw saffron in the cupboard.
那是一家法式餐廳 我看到櫥櫃上有番紅花
-Sharp? -It's a type of spice in the iris family.
-泛紅花？ -那是一種香料，屬於鳶尾科
I'll go get it.
我去拿
You're going there when it's full of Yachas now?
那裡到處都是夜叉，你還要去嗎？
-I must go. -Take me with you then!
-我必須去 -那就帶上我！
-I'll go too. -Hey!
-我也去 -喂！
-Why should I go there? -We're a family.
-我為什麼要去啊？ -我們是一家人
I'm sorry, but my life isn't mine.
對不起，我的命不屬於我
-It's Madame Ryu's. -We have no time. Let's go.
-它是柳閣長的 -沒時間了，快走吧
Take care of Mrs. Boss.
好好照顧頭目夫人
Please hang in there until I get back.
請妳堅持到我回來
They're having a damn feast, huh?
他們簡直是在享受盛宴啊
How do we get past them?
我們怎麼穿過去？
Their movements are slower than before.
比起之前，他們的行動慢下來了
Where do you think you're going?
你要去哪裡？
Lord Lee Rang!
李朗大人！
They can't even see that?
那麼近都看不見嗎？
They can't see us without the light. They only react to noises.
他們在暗處看不見我們 只對聲音有反應
So we approach them in silence?
我們悄悄靠近他們？
No. We'll use that to our advantage.
不，我們要反過來利用這一點
Shin-ju, get the iris from the restaurant.
申炷，你去餐廳拿鳶尾花
We'll lure them to one side in the loudest way possible.
我們用最吵的方式把他們引向一邊
Should I just scream with all my might?
要我用盡全力叫喊嗎？
-If you do, Shin-ju will be in danger. -Then?
-那會讓申炷有危險 -那怎麼辦？
The record player.
唱片機
Let's move it over there and lure them.
我們把它搬到那邊，引他們過去
At the sound of music, they'll swarm there.
他們聽到音樂聲，都會衝過去的
Let's go.
走吧
So what's the plan now?
現在怎麼辦？
Look here. Out of the four mercenaries, the poison bender is dead.
看這裡，僱傭兵團的四個人中 下毒的那個已經死了
So he's a goner.
不必考慮他
Now it's the three of them and the three of us.
現在是他們三個對抗我們三個
What are their powers?
他們會什麼法術？
The first one is Yuki-onna, the snow lady.
第一個是雪女
You guys saw her earlier.
你們之前見過她
The second guy's name was, Gamma-ray. Something with "gamma."
第二個叫什麼來著，好像是什麼“蟆”
-Oogama, that's what she said. -She's right. It's Oogama.
-大蝦蟆，她說的是大蝦蟆 -沒錯，大蝦蟆
And what's that?
那是什麼東西？
A centuries-old Japanese toad demon.
一種活了幾百年的日本蟾蜍怪
I've read about it.
我在書上看到過
He's an airhead who's just strong.
他頭腦簡單，四肢發達
OOGAMA: A GIANT TOAD DEMON FROM JAPANESE FABLES
（大蝦蟆：日本怪談中 巨大的蟾蜍怪）
-I'll take care of him. -Sure.
-交給我好了 -沒問題
The problem is the third guy. Gosh, I don't know his name or power.
問題在於第三個 天哪，他的名字和法術，我都不知道
And he seems to be the boss.
而且他似乎是團長
Oh, well. I'll deal with this one.
好吧，我來對付他
How will you catch all three?
你要怎麼一下子抓住三個妖怪？
Well, I gave them the golden ruler, so they should come for the stone now.
我把金尺給他們了 所以他們應該會來搶奪守護石
I'll be the bait.
我來當誘餌
Is that necessary? They must be looking for you too.
有必要嗎？他們一定也在找你呢
-They'll come find you. -Gosh.
-他們會來找你的 -天哪
I don't have time to sit back and wait, you hear?
我沒時間坐在這裡等，知道嗎？
Because some prick let a Yacha loose at the hotel.
因為有個混蛋 在飯店裡放出了一個夜叉
-Damn it. Then let's all go together. -It's fine.
-該死，那我們一起去 -不用了
Even if you took the antidote, it'll take some time to take effect.
雖然你們吃了解藥 但它還需要一段時間才能起效
I'll lure them in. In the meantime, you guys recover.
我去引他們的同時，你們先恢復體力
-Yeon. -Yeah?
-阿硯 -嗯？
-Just in case. -Wh-- Goodness.
-以防萬一 -天哪
Really?
真的嗎？
Hey, why give me a gun when they aren't even humans, huh?
他們又不是人類，妳給我槍做什麼？
If things go awry, you must call me.
萬一出問題，一定要通知我
I'm not a kid. Here, take this back.
我不是小孩子，給，拿回去
-Yeon! -Yeah?
-阿硯！ -嗯？
Just one last thing.
還有最後一樣東西
Yeah, all right. I'll be back.
好了，我會回來的
Excuse me!
喂！
-Please take me with you. -Get lost.
-請你帶我一起走吧 -滾開
You beat me up earlier, remember?
你之前打過我的，記得嗎？
-You not sorry? -Get lost.
-你不覺得內疚嗎？ -滾開
Don't be like that. Let's make it out together.
別這樣，我們一起闖出去
-I'll help out. -Don't touch it!
-我可以幫忙 -別碰它！
Shush!
噓！
I'll kill you.
我要殺了你
I'll be invisible.
我會藏好的
President?
會長？
President, it's me.
會長，是我啊
Hurry, hurry!
快跑！
Don't come here, you!
別過來，喂！
Boss, quick! Turn it on!
老大，快打開唱片機！
I'm not the kind to die in a place like this!
我可不能死在這種地方啊！
Stop pushing!
別擠我！
Geez.
天哪
Where the hell are they? Damn it!
他們究竟去哪了？真是的！
What's this smell?
這是什麼氣味？
I definitely know this smell.
我絕對聞到過
What's this now?
又怎麼了？
Who are you?
你是誰？
Please help me.
請你救救我
-I've seen this old man somewhere. -At Myoyeongak, sir.
-我好像在哪裡見過這個老人 -是在妙緣閣，先生
Oh, right! I remember you.
對！我記得你
You're an indigenous god?
你是本土神嗎？
Yes, sir. But where on earth are we?
是的，但是，這究竟是什麼地方？
-Why am I suddenly in the woods? -Why don't you tell me?
-我為什麼突然來到樹林裡了？ -這應該問你吧
-How did you get in here? -Well.
-你怎麼過來的？ -我…
I was at the hotel until a while ago.
我剛剛還在飯店裡
But monsters started chasing me, so I jumped into an open room and…
怪物開始追趕我 所以我跳進一個敞著門的房間…
Goodness, how pathetic.
天哪，真可憐
This place is more dangerous.
這裡更危險
It's teeming with Japanese demons.
到處都是日本妖怪
Sir! Could you please take me with you?
求求你帶我一起走吧
I sprained my ankle while running from the monsters.
我在躲避怪物的時候扭傷了腳踝
Gosh, I'm too busy for you to bother me like this.
天哪，我已經很忙了 你還要這樣麻煩我
Geez. Get on.
真是的，上來吧
-Thank you, sir. -Geez.
-謝謝 -天哪
How?
怎麼會？
The poison bender from earlier smelled just like you.
之前那個下毒的妖怪 和你散發著同樣的氣味
A strangely unpleasant sweet smell.
一種討人厭的奇怪甜味
This?
是這個嗎？
Caramels? You're one of the mercenaries.
焦糖？你是僱傭兵團的成員
-You're quite fast. -Are you the boss?
-你的反應很快喔 -你是團長嗎？
My name is Nyudo.
我叫入道
Onyudo.
大入道
-I like you. -You're not my type.
-我喜歡你 -你不是我喜歡的類型
What?
怎麼回事？
Why is my body there?
我的身體怎麼在你那裡？
You see, Onyudo has a meaning.
大入道這個名字是有含義的
It means, I'm a body-switching demon.
意思是我是可以交換身體的妖怪
ONYUDO: A BODY-SWITCHING DEMON FROM JAPANESE FABLES
（大入道：日本怪談中 可以交換身體的妖怪）
What do you think? Do you like my new body?
怎麼樣？喜歡我的新身體嗎？
My goodness.
真是的
Give me back my nice body.
把我好看的身體還給我
Oh, dear.
天哪
You just had to stab me with a sword, didn't you?
誰叫你非要刺我一劍，是吧？
You think you're above us, huh?
你以為你高我們一等嗎？
Being a mountain god of Joseon means nothing.
朝鮮山神不過如此
By the way, where is the treasure?
對了，寶物在哪裡？
I'll never give it to you pricks.
我永遠不會把它交給你們這些混帳
What? Darn it.
什麼？該死
Where did you put the treasure?
你把寶物放在哪裡了？
It's not there?
不在身上嗎？
It can't be…
不可能…
Hey, stop it. It's just going to weigh me down.
別塞了，這只會增加我的負擔
Shit.
該死
-The treasure's not with me. -Is that so?
-寶物不在我這裡 -是嗎？
Guess the others have it then.
那就是在另外兩人手裡
No!
不要！
You can't.
你不能走
Boss, hurry and turn it on!
老大，快打開唱片機！
Where did that bastard go?
那個混蛋去哪了？
I will kill you with my own hands.
我要親手殺了你
I wonder if Hong-joo and Moo-yeong are safe.
不知道紅酒和無影安不安全
What if he pretends to be me?
如果他假扮成我怎麼辦？
My treasure has been stolen, and my body is in this state.
我的寶物被偷了，身體變成這副樣子
I don't even know if Rang is alive.
我甚至不知道阿朗是生是死
Where did everything start to fall apart?
一切是從哪裡開始急轉直下的？
Is she still alive?
她還活著嗎？
I can hear her breathing.
我能聽到呼吸聲
What if she turns into a monster and tries to eat us?
如果她變成怪物 想要吃掉我們怎麼辦？
-It's fine, as long as she's breathing. -This is getting me so anxious.
-只要她還有呼吸就沒事 -我快要急瘋了
-What about Jae-yoo? -He went to find Madame Ryu.
-載宇呢？ -他去找柳閣長了
I want to leave! I don't want to die in a place like this!
我想離開！我不想死在這種地方！
-Orchid! -Just leave her be.
-蘭草！ -別管她
He said not to go out.
他說過不能出去的
Move, you little brat. Staying in here is terrifying!
讓開，死丫頭，待在這裡太可怕了！
You don't know what's out there!
妳不知道外面有什麼！
-Madame Ryu might be back. -I'm not letting you out.
-可能是柳閣長回來了 -我不會放妳出去的
Have you lost your mind?
妳瘋了嗎？
Did you forget Lord Lee Yeon and Lord Lee Rang saving you?
妳是不是忘了 李硯大人和李朗大人救過妳啊？
I owe them my life too!
我也欠他們一條命！
-So annoying. -Don't get too upset.
-煩死了 -別著急
If she stops breathing, I'll finish her.
如果她斷氣的話，我會解決她的
We can't die in vain at a place like this.
我們不能白白死在這種地方
Open the door!
開門！
Close it!
關門！
Saffron, saffron…
番紅花…
Saffron.
番紅花
Okay, got it.
找到了
I don't want to die! I don't want to die!
我不想死！
Hey, you prick! Get it together.
混蛋，振作起來！
Hey, get it together! Calm down!
振作起來，冷靜點！
I'm sorry, but I'm going!
對不起，我要跑了！
No!
不要啊！
Go. Go!
快走！
Do you think we'll get out of here?
你覺得我們能走出這裡嗎？
Why would you say that?
為什麼這樣問？
No reason.
不為什麼
Strangely, I have a bad feeling.
說來奇怪，我有一種不祥的預感
Just like the morning of the mountain god exam.
就像選拔山神那天早上一樣
-But you passed the exam. -Instead, I lost what I loved the most.
-但是妳通過了 -可我失去了我最愛的人
You guys.
你們
You didn't lose me.
妳沒有失去我
I've only had eyes for you.
我的眼裡只有妳
Hong-joo, you only had eyes for Lee Yeon.
紅酒，妳的眼裡只有李硯
But I only had eyes for you all along.
但是我的眼裡始終只有妳一個
I wanted you.
我想得到妳
Though I knew you wouldn't be mine.
但我知道妳不可能屬於我
Why do first loves always go wrong?
為什麼初戀總是沒有好結果？
Because it's your first love?
因為是初戀嗎？
What would you do if your first love took the treasure for herself?
如果你的初戀將寶物佔為己有 你會怎麼做？
Well, that's a difficult one.
這個問題很難回答
Better than losing it to Yeon.
總比輸給阿硯好吧
-Guys. -Yeon!
-兩位 -阿硯！
Why are you alone? What about the mercenaries?
怎麼只有你一個人？僱傭兵團呢？
Well, I was ambushed by them.
我被他們伏擊了
Don't tell me you ran away.
你該不會是逃跑了吧
-Instead, I found their hideout. -Where?
-沒有，我找到了他們的藏身處 -在哪裡？
But how are you guys feeling? Has the poison been fully neutralized?
但是你們怎麼樣了？ 毒藥的效力徹底消失了嗎？
The bleeding has stopped, but we're not fully recovered yet.
流血止住了，但身體還沒有完全恢復
Good. I'll lure them to our hideout.
很好，我要把他們引入我們的藏身處
Well, let's hurry. Now is our chance.
快走吧，我們的機會來了
Let's go.
走吧
Nyudo!
入道！
It's the mercenaries.
是僱傭兵團
If I attract their attention now, I'll be dead meat.
現在被他們發現的話，我就死定了
I can't fight them with this body.
這個身體是沒辦法與他們抗衡的
Nyudo!
入道！
Hey, Nyudo isn't here.
入道不在這裡
How strange.
真奇怪
-I heard footsteps nearby. -Maybe it's one of the mountain gods.
-我明明聽到附近有腳步聲 -也許是其中一個山神
I hope it's the nine-tailed fox.
希望是那隻九尾狐
-Here. -Please!
-這裡 -拜託！
Please go elsewhere!
拜託你們去別的地方吧！
I don't think he's here.
他應該不在這裡
Let's go.
走吧
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
Hold on.
等等
Perhaps, this may be an opportunity.
也許這是個機會
They don't know our bodies switched.
他們不知道我們交換了身體
But if they find out…
但是一旦被發現…
Over here!
這邊！
-Nyudo!
-入道！
Hey, where were you?
你去哪裡了？
What's with you?
你怎麼了？
Charge forward!
衝啊！
Boss!
老大！
Hang on to me!
靠著我！
-Lord Lee Rang. -Shin-ju, you got it?
-李朗大人 -申炷，東西拿到了嗎？
-Let's go. -He was bitten!
-我們走 -他被咬傷了！
-Let's go together. -You son of a--
-我們一起走吧 -你這個混蛋
I didn't mean to put you at risk!
我不是故意害你冒險的！
-Why you-- -We save the living!
-你怎麼… -我們救生者！
Yes, the living.
對，生者
What should we do, Boss?
怎麼辦，老大？
-Come here, you bastard! -Let's go together!
-過來，你這個混蛋！ -我們一起走吧！
Just die!
去死吧！
Help me, help me!
救救我！
-What are you doing? -We've waited long enough.
-妳要做什麼？ -我們等得夠久了
-Lord Lee Rang isn't coming! -He will!
-李朗大人不會來的！ -他會的！
What happens if he doesn't?
如果他不來呢？
Madame always said to live or to die is our own decision to make.
閣長總是教育我們 生死是由自己決定的
-I want to live. -Let's wait a little longer.
-我想活命 -我們再等一下
-Move! -Stop it!
-讓開！ -住手！
-Orchid! -You stay out of this.
-蘭草姊！ -妳別管
I'm sorry.
對不起
What's with you?
你怎麼了？
I asked you a question.
我在問你話呢
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
What's with the injury?
你的傷是怎麼回事？
The nine-tailed fox got to me.
被九尾狐傷到的
Idiot. Nyudo's an idiot.
笨蛋，入道是個笨蛋
And after all that bragging.
之前還一直吹噓呢
Shut up!
閉嘴！
By the way, are you really Nyudo?
話說，你真的是入道嗎？
-What? -You can just switch bodies with the fox.
-什麼？ -你可以和那隻狐狸交換身體啊
Don't tell me.
該不會是
It's been switched.
換過了吧？
Gosh. Without Ushiuchibo, we can't tell his original form.
天哪，沒有了牛打坊 我們看不出他的本體
You're right.
沒錯
If you really are Nyudo, why didn't you switch bodies with him?
如果你真的是入道 為什麼沒有和他交換身體呢？
That bastard knows more about us than we thought.
那個混蛋比我們想像中更了解我們
-He even knows about my power. -How did he know?
-他甚至知道我的法術 -他怎麼會知道呢？
That reminds me.
這倒是讓我想起來了
He did know about me too.
他確實也知道我的身份
Shouldn't we tell boss?
要不要告訴團長？
Boss?
團長？
Where's the boss? You should know.
團長在哪裡？你應該知道的
The bastard who stole my body wasn't the boss?
偷走我身體的混蛋不是團長嗎？
Shinigami Mercenaries has five members, not four.
死神僱傭兵團的成員有五個 不是四個
Then where is--
那他在哪裡…
Don't tell me.
該不會是…
And the mercenaries?
僱傭兵團呢？
Still no word from them?
他們還沒有消息嗎？
Their boss is at the Bando Hotel.
他們的團長在坂東飯店
Satori is?
悟嗎？
Yes. Now that Satori has joined the game,
是的，既然悟已經加入遊戲
for people and demons alike, that hotel…
對人類和妖怪來說，那家飯店…
will be a slaughterhouse.
將會變成屠宰場
Hurry up.
快點
One, two, three.
一、二、三
From now on, you can't take one step out of this room.
從現在起，不准你們走出房間一步
Until you die.
直到死為止
Hong-joo!
紅酒！
How disappointing.
真讓人失望
What is the reason Moo-yeong…
無影來到這個時代…
-Cheon Moo-yeong! -…came to this era?
-千無影！ -…是為了什麼？
Don't you have an idea?
妳不知道嗎？
He's trying to awaken something with the golden ruler.
他想用金尺喚醒某樣東西
It can't be! He can't wake that up!
不可以！他不能喚醒那東西！
Don't even think of having hope.
別想著抱有任何希望
Don't die, Moo-yeong.
不要死啊，無影
Please have my back, so I can fight.
請你支持我，讓我全力戰鬥
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳